In this video, we're going to talk about
classes in Dynamics SL and compare them
to the experience in Business Central
where you can use templates to
streamline the creation of customers,
vendors, and items.
In this example, we'll focus on customer
class. Classes are used to group similar
customers together for reporting
purposes.
Classes also used to supply default
settings when a new record is created.
Let's go into SL and look at a customer
class that I've already created.
In this example, we're grouping our
customers by region.
And I have some preset information for
customers in this class.
In my class, you can see the default
receivables price class,
terms, and accounts
I want to default for any customers
assigned to this customer class.
Next, if we go to customer maintenance,
create a new customer,
see how the defaults tab is populated
from the retail class
defaulted into the screen from AR setup.
Notice that the OM GL accounts are
blank.
Now, if we assign the region customer
class, we can see the default
information has been updated,
and OM GL accounts tab has been
populated with the information we
entered under the region customer class
setup.
Now, let's look at Business Central and
how we can create templates that allow
us to easily set up information we want
for new customers.
First, we need to navigate to customer
templates.
You'll select the search icon,
enter customer templates, and then
choose customer templates from the
search results.
Give the new template a name, and then
start filling in the information you
want to default for new or existing
customers.
If you've noticed, I don't see the
credit limit or sales person fields on
the template form.
I will simply select the personalized
form,
find the fields that I want to add, and
add them onto the template window.
Now that I've added the credit limit and
sales person fields to the template, I
will select the proper values for each.
Next, I'll set the default business and
customer posting groups so that the
correct sales and accounts receivable
accounts are used for customers in this
group.
Finally, let's set the default region
dimension buying so that transactions
posted to the sales account are
categorized correctly.
Now that we have the customer template
configured, let's create a new customer
and apply the template.
When I select to create a new customer,
you can see the various templates I've
created are displayed and I can select
the region template.
In the customer window, you can see how
the credit limit and sales person have
defaulted in front, as well as the right
business and customer posting groups.
We can also navigate to the dimension
for the customer and see that the
correct region has been defaulted there
as well.
If you created a customer with values
you want to use for another customer,
you can create a template from an
existing customer card.
Lastly, if I had existing customers that
I want to apply this template to, I
could do that as well.
That's a quick look at how we can use
templates in Business Central to
streamline data creation and improve
data accuracy.
To learn more about Business Central,
see the following resources.